

samuelsholib12@gmail.com | 2065035342 | Seattle, WA 98106

Summary

Dedicated hardworking and self-motivated programmer with over five years of experience in various disciplines working both overseas and in the United States developed deep customer connections that could potentially promote sustained gain. Currently, I am in the last month of the University of Washington's Coding Boot Camp And seeking a position as a front or back-end developer, or internships at tech companies to use my excellent programming, problem-solving skills and working knowledge of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, express.js, React.js, jQuery, MySQL, MongoDB, Bootstrap, Bulma, and handlebars to accomplish the job requirements for the position that I could be assigned to.

Skills

- Friendly and Outgoing
- Verbal and Written Communication
- Customer Service
- Problem-Solving
- Organizational Skills
- Team Management
- Conflict Resolution
- HTML

- CSS
- JavaScript
- ReactJS
- NodeJS
- Express.JS
- MySQL
- MongoDB

Experience

Lyft | Seattle, WA **Driver**

11/2017 - Current

- Monitored traffic conditions and applied defensive strategies to avoid accidents.
- Achieved consistently high customer scores due to exceptional service.
- Offered riders information about local attractions and restaurants.
- Maintained safe driving history with no critical incidents over 3-year timeframe.

Securitas Security Services USA | Seattle, WA

Unarmed Security Officer

10/2018 - 08/2019

- Guarded entrances and exits against unauthorized entry.
- Provided friendly and professional assistance to employees, visitors and customers.
- Wrote reports outlining thefts, unauthorized access violations or other unusual occurrences to help support later criminal or civil actions.
- Patrolled large commercial facility on irregular schedule to look for suspicious activities.
- Collaborated with local law enforcement agencies to support criminal investigations.

Omo-Kuraz Sugar Factory | Jinka, SNNPRS

Field Coordinator

09/2015 - 05/2016

- Coordinated and managed schedules for team of 38 field service technicians.
- Informed clients about project progress, delays and issues and negotiated resolution.
- Facilitated weekly project meetings to maintain schedule, budget, and service delivery requirements.

- Managed schedule for 38 technicians and supervised workload based on capacity and training.
- Monitored employee work levels and optimized performance with strategic approaches.
- Eliminated knowledge gaps by managing continuous training and mentoring strategies for new and junior personnel.
- Collaborated with supervisor to manage logistics for varying stages of installation projects.

Education and Training

Washington State University | Pullman, WA **Bachelor of Science** in Agricultural Biotechnology 07/2021

University of Washington | Seattle, WA Full Stack Web Development